Felix Mönckemeyer

felix.moenckemeyer@gmail.com · +49 176 2354 9970 · Köln, Germany

Highly motivated **Software Developer** (IoT & Fullstack) With a strong interest in complex problems. More than 3 years of experience in the development of industrial software from machine to the cloud. **Project management**, Requirements analysis, Planning, Implementation, Testing and Documentation.



"I want to develop customised solutions and use cutting-edge technologies to deliver simpler, faster and more reliable software."

EXPERIENCES

• vivenu GmbH

Backend Developer

Delivering a reliable, scalable and simple ticketing experience for our API-First customers.

Since September 2021

• Senseering GmbH

Full Stack Software Engineer - Köln

Developer of a decentralised data sharing platform & Software Consultant - IoT Infrastructure Solutions in multiple manufacturing related projects.

April 2020 - August 2021

• Senseering GmbH

Software Engineer - Aachen

Developer of a decentralised data sharing platform in the sense of GAIA-X.

September 2018 - April 2020

• WZL of the RWTH Aachen

Working Student - Aachen

Collecting PLC and sensor data for an internal research data library. Improving the accessibility of real-time and historical data via an institute-wide MQTT server and subsequent raw data collection.

April 2018 - April 2020

TRAINING

• B.Sc. Informatik

RWTH Aachen University Herbst 2014- Herbst 2018

SKILLS

Prorgramming Languages & Databases

Nodejs, Typescript, Vue, Python, MySQL, Mongodb, Influxdb, Redis

Cloud & Technologies

S3/Azure Blob Storage, EC2, CodeBuild, CodePipeline, CloudFront, Grafana, docker, Node Red, Github Actions, DynamoDB, AWS Cognito, Auth0, IOTA, Nginx, Route 53, ELB, API Gateway, AWS Lambda

Languages

Geman, English

PROJECTS

• warrant [NemesisFLX/warrant]

Warrant price calculator with a neat typescript interface *Warrants, Typescript, Trading, Open Source*

• iBoll [Bollfilter IoT Platform]

Analyzing realtime iot data and service deployment with anomaly detection

Serverless, Vue, MQTT, Manufacturing

• spaicer [spaicer.de]

Scalable Adaptive Production Systems through AI-Based Resilience Optimisation - Project Responsibility Project management, IoT, Machine Learning, KI

• obsidian [NemesisFLX/obsidian]

A Nodejs based immutability layer for (industrial) data *Nodejs, IOTA*

• MyDataEconomy [mydataeconomy.com]

Decentralized IoT data sharing platform for sovereign data exchange.

GAIA-X, Nodejs, Docker, IOTA, InfluxDB





